Guide to the Savage Mining Company and Associated Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Financial Records, 1860-1942; Series IV; 33.5; (21 boxes)
  - SAVAGE MINING COMPANY
    - General Records
      - Cashbook [individual pages], 1882-83, 1889 (Box 44, Folder 748-751)
      - Cashbook [daybook], 1889-97 (Box 44p, Folder 752)
      - Cashbook [individual pages] (Box 44, Folder 753)
      - Daybook, 1862-63 (Box 44, Folder 754)
      - Gross product of mine, 1865 Nov (Box 44, Folder 755)
      - Memorandum on bank draft (Box 44, Folder 756)
      - Pump expenses, 1879-80 (Box 44, Folder 757)
      - Receipts, 1860-63 (Box 44, Folder 758-761)
        See also: Oversize, Box 87, folder 1425
      - Receipts, 1864-67 (Box 45, Folder 762-775)
      - Receipts, 1867-74 (Box 46, Folder 776-797)
      - Receipts, 1875-79 (Box 47, Folder 798-813)
      - Receipts, 1880-82 (Box 48, Folder 814-828)
      - Receipts, 1883-86 (Box 49, Folder 829-842)
      - Receipts, 1887-88 (Box 50, Folder 843-854)
      - Receipts, 1888-89 (Box 51, Folder 855-866)
      - Receipts, 1889-90 (Box 52, Folder 867-874)
      - Receipts, 1890 (Box 53, Folder 875-881)
      - Receipts, 1891-92 (Box 54, Folder 882-896)
      - Receipts, 1893-96 (Box 55, Folder 897-913)
      - Receipts, 1897-99 (Box 56, Folder 914-927)
      - Receipts, 1900-03 (Box 57, Folder 928-943)
      - Receipts, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 944-946)
    - Superintendent's Records
      - Accounts, 1875-77 (Box 58, Folder 947)
      - Accounts, 1881 (Box 58a, Folder 948)
      - Accounts, 1883-86 (Box 58a, Folder 949-952)
      - Accounts, n.d. (Box 58a, Folder 953)
      - Drafts on president, 1862-64 (Box 58a, Folder 954)
      - Drafts on president, 1868-76 (Box 58a, Folder 955-956)
      - Drafts on president, 1868-76 (Box 58b, Folder 957)
      - Loan note, 1864 (Box 59, Folder 958)
      - Receipt book, 1863-64 (Box 59, Folder 959)
      - Receipt book, 1865-66 (Box 59, Folder 960)
    - Bank Records
      - B. F. Hastings & Co.
        - Check stubs, 1864 (Box 59c, Folder 961)
        - Check stubs, 1864 (Box 59d, Folder 961a)
      - Bank of California, Virginia City
        - Account books, 1866-68 (Box 59, Folder 962-963)
        - Account books, 1871-72 (Box 59, Folder 964-965)
        - Checks, 1883 (Box 59, Folder 966)
        - Checks, 1895-99 (Box 59, Folder 967)
        - Checks, 1902-30,n.d. (Box 59, Folder 968)
        - Check stubs, 1864-72 (Box 59, Folder 969)
          See also: Oversize for folder 979, Box 87, folder 1426
        - Check stubs, 1864-1872 (Box 59e, Folder 970)
        - Check stubs, 1864-1872 (Box 59f, Folder 971)
        - Check stubs, 1864-1872 (Box 59g, Folder 972)
        - Check stubs (Box 59, Folder 973-974)
          Existence and Location of Copies
          Folders 973-74 have been microfilmed and are represented here by copyflow produced from the film. Call number of film: MS Vault / Microfilm / 674.
        - Check stubs, 1864-1872 (Box 59h, Folder 975)
        - Check stubs, 1864-1872 (Box 59i, Folder 976)
        - Check stubs, 1864-1872 (Box 59j, Folder 977)
        - Check stubs, 1864-1872 (Box 59k, Folder 978)
        - Check stubs, 1864-1872 (Box 59l, Folder 979)
        - Check stubs, 1864-1872 (Box 59m, Folder 980)
        - Check stubs, 1864-1872 (Box 59n, Folder 981)
        - Check stubs, 1864-1872 (Box 59, Folder 982-985)
          Folders 982-85 have been microfilmed and are represented here by copyflow produced from the film. Call number of film: MS Vault / Microfilm / 674.
        - Check stubs, 1872-1898 (Box 60, Folder 984-985)
          See also: Oversize, Box 88, folder 1429a
        - Check stubs, 1872-1898 (Box 60a, Folder 986)
        - Check stubs, 1872-1898 (Box 60b, Folder 987)
        - Check stubs, 1872-1898 (Box 60c, Folder 988)
        - Check stubs, 1872-1898 (Box 60d, Folder 989)
        - Check stubs, 1872-1898 (Box 60e, Folder 990)
        - Check stubs, 1872-1898 (Box 60f, Folder 991)
        - Check stubs, 1872-1898 (Box 60g, Folder 992)
        - Check stubs, 1872-1898 (Box 60h, Folder 993)
        - Check stubs, 1872-1898 (Box 60i, Folder 994)
        - Miscellaneous, 1880-81 (Box 60, Folder 995)
      - Nevada Bank of San Francisco, Virginia City
        - Account book, 1876-77 (Box 60, Folder 996)
        - Account book, 1893-95 (Box 60, Folder 997)
        - Checks, 1876-77 (Box 60, Folder 998)
      - Checks, 1887-95 (Box 60, Folder 999-1004)
        - Interest account records, 1878-94,n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1005)
        - Miscellaneous, 1888-92 (Box 60, Folder 1006)
      - Paxton & Thornburgh
        - Checks, 1862 (Box 60, Folder 1007)
        - Check stubs, 1863-64 (Box 60, Folder 1008-1010)
          See also: Oversize, Box 88, folders 1429b-33
        - Miscellaneous, 1862 (Box 60, Folder 1011)
      - Wells Fargo & Company
        - Account book, 1861-62 (Box 60, Folder 1012)
        - Account record, 1877-80 (Box 61, Folder 1013)
        - Checks, 1878-88 (Box 61, Folder 1014)
        - Check stubs, 1877-85 (Box 61a, Folder 1014a)
        - Check stubs, 1877-85 (Box 61b, Folder 1015)
        - Interest records, 1878-80 (Box 61, Folder 1016)
      - Unidentified bank
        - Check stubs, 1866-67 (Box 61, Folder 1017)
        - Check stubs, 1886-96 (Box 61, Folder 1018-1022)
        - Interest account record, 1889 Mar (Box 61, Folder 1023)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Accounts, 1864-90, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1024-1025)
        See also: Oversize, Box 87, folder 1427
  - SCORPION MINING COMPANY
    - Accounts, 1882 Apr, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1026)
    - Unpaid bills, 1880 (Box 61, Folder 1027)
    - Receipts, 1879-85,n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1028)
  - SIERRA NEVADA, MEXICAN AND UNION COMPANY
    - Receipts, 1894 Apr (Box 61, Folder 1029)
  - SIERRA NEVADA MINING COMPANY
    - Receipts, 1894 Apr (Box 61, Folder 1030)
  - THOMPSON MILL
    - Receipts, 1886 (Box 61, Folder 1031)
  - WARD COMBINATION COMPANY
    - Receipts, 1894 Apr (Box 61, Folder 1032)
  - UNIDENTIFIED FINANCIAL RECORDS
    - Ledger, 1860-61 (Box 61c, Folder 1033)
    - Daybook, 1876-77 (Box 61d, Folder 1034)
    - Daybook, 1875-78 (Box 61e, Folder 1035)
    - Miscellaneous daily account balances, 1877 May
      See: Oversize, Box 88, folder 1428
    - Miscellaneous accounts, 1864-91, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1036-1037)
    - Bank records: check stubs, 1863-83 (Box 61, Folder 1038-1039)
    - Bank records: check stubs, 1887-1902 (Box 62, Folder 1040-1043)
    - Bank records: checkbook cover, 1873
      See: Oversize, Box 88, folder 1429
    - Receipts, 1860-1942, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1044-1046)
- Inventory Records, 1868-91; Series V; 11.5; (4 boxes)
  Series V, Inventory Reports, is arranged alphabetically by name and within each company annual reports are followed by monthly, weekly, and daily. Material whose corporate origin can not be identified has been placed at the end.
  - ATCHISON MILL
    - Inventory of property, 1872 Jul 1 (Box 63, Folder 1047)
    - Store house accounts, 1869
      See: Oversize, Box 94, folder 1472
  - CHOLLAR-NORCROSS-SAVAGE SHAFT CO.
    - Inventory of joint Savage-Norcross materials on hand at the shaft, 1883 Feb 1 (Box 63, Folder 1048)
  - GOULD AND CURRY ASSAY OFFICE
    - List of articles [inventory for sale of equipment ?], 1868 Feb 3 (Box 63, Folder 1049)
  - HALE & NORCROSS MINING COMPANY
    - Monthly inventories, 1887-91 (Box 63, Folder 1050-1051)
      See also: Savage monthly inventories, Box 63, folder 1062
    - Monthly lumber/timber inventories, 1887-88 (Box 63, Folder 1052)
    - Monthly lumber/timber inventory, 1891 Apr (Box 63, Folder 1053)
    - Invoice book and inventory book, 1872-83 (Box 63a, Folder 1054)
    - Miscellaneous inventory, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1055)
      See also: Savage miscellaneous, Box 66, folder 1120
  - SAVAGE MILL
    - Inventory of property, 1872 Jul 1 (Box 63, Folder 1056)
    - Store house accounts, 1869-70
      See: Oversize, Box 94, folder 1473
    - Supplies account, 1870 (Box 63, Folder 1057)
  - SAVAGE MINING COMPANY
    - Savage Assay Office
      - Store and stock expense summary, 1871-75
        See: Oversize, Box 89, folder 1434-38
      - Articles in assay office, 1875 Jul 17 (Box 63, Folder 1058)
    - Savage Mine
      - Annual inventories, 1880-81 (Box 63, Folder 1059)
      - Annual inventories, 1883-[86] (Box 63b, Folder 1060)
      - Monthly inventories [ledger], 1883-91 (Box 63c, Folder 1061)
      - Monthly inventories [daybook], 1889-91 (Box 63d, Folder 1062)
      - Monthly inventories [daybook], drafts, 1887-88 (Box 63, Folder 1063)
      - Store House Accounts
        - Ledgers, 1866-78 (Box 63e, Folder 1064)
        - Ledgers, 1866-78 (Box 63f, Folder 1065)
        - Ledgers, 1866-78 (Box 63g, Folder 1066)
        - Ledgers, 1866-78 (Box 63h, Folder 1067)
        - Ledgers, 1866-78 (Box 63i, Folder 1068)
        - Ledgers, 1866-78 (Box 63j, Folder 1069)
        - Ledgers, 1866-78 (Box 63k, Folder 1070)
        - Ledgers, 1866-78 (Box 63l, Folder 1071)
        - Ledgers, 1866-78 (Box 63m, Folder 1072)
        - Ledgers, 1866-78 (Box 63n, Folder 1073)
        - Ledgers, 1866-78 (Box 63o, Folder 1074)
        - Ledgers, 1866-78 (Box 63p, Folder 1075)
        - Ledgers, 1866-78 (Box 63q, Folder 1076)
        - Store-house keeper's daily reports, 1873-74 (Box 63, Folder 1077-1089)
      - Store-house keeper's daily reports, 1875-76 Aug (Box 64, Folder 1090-1105)
        - Store-house keeper's daily reports, 1876 Oct-77 (Box 65, Folder 1106-1111)
        - [Store house] order book, 1876-79,1883 (Box 65a, Folder 1112)
      - Monthly lumber inventories, 1865 (Box 66, Folder 1113)
      - Monthly lumber inventories, 1884 (Box 66, Folder 1114)
      - Monthly lumber inventories, 1887-88 (Box 66, Folder 1115)
      - Monthly lumber inventories, 1891 (Box 66, Folder 1116)
      - Lumber inventories [daybook], 1884-85 (Box 66, Folder 1117)
      - Wood inventory, 1880 (Box 66, Folder 1118)
      - Freight account for material received and lumber received, 1865 (Box 66a, Folder 1119)
      - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1120)
    - Savage property at Chollar-Norcross-Savage Shaft
      - Inventories, 1883-84 (Box 66, Folder 1121)
  - SCORPION MINING COMPANY
    - Lumber inventory, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1122)
  - UNIDENTIFIED INVENTORY RECORDS
    - Monthly inventory ledger, 1879-81 (Box 66b, Folder 1123)
    - Wood inventory ledgers, 1871-77 (Box 66c, Folder 1124)
    - Wood inventory ledgers, 1871-77 (Box 66d, Folder 1125)
    - Memorandum of wood, lumber etc. received, 1875-82 (Box 66e, Folder 1126)
    - Miscellaneous wood, lumber, etc. inventories, 1876,1891,n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1127)
    - Miscellaneous inventories, 1865,1871,n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1128-1131)
    - Notes on material, 1887, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1132)
- Pay Roll Records, 1861-1912; Series VI; 8.25; (13 boxes)
  Series VI, Pay Roll Records, is arranged alphabetically by company name. The arrangement within each company follows the pattern ledgers, daybooks (time book), and other material. Material whose corporate origin can not be identified has been placed at the end.
  - COMBINATION [CHOLLAR-NORCROSS-SAVAGE] SHAFT CO.
    - Time book, 1912 (Box 67, Folder 1133)
  - CROWN POINT MINING COMPANY
    - Pay roll record, 1880 Sep (Box 67, Folder 1134)
  - HALE & NORCROSS MINING COMPANY
    - Time book, 1882-84 (Box 67, Folder 1135-1148)
    - Time book, 1884-86 (Box 68, Folder 1149-1162)
    - Time book, 1886-87 (Box 69, Folder 1163-1174)
    - Time book, 1891 (Box 69, Folder 1175)
    - Pay roll record, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1176)
  - LADY BRYAN
    - Pay roll records, 1876-77
      See: Oversize, Box 89, folder 1439
    - Miscellaneous, 1871, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1177)
  - SANTIAGO MILL
    - Pay roll records, 1882, n.d.
      See: Oversize, Box 89, folder 1440
    - Time book, 1881-82
      See: Savage time book, 1883, Box 71, folder 1199
  - SAVAGE MILL
    - Pay roll record, 1871 Jun
      See: Oversize, Box 89, folder 1441
  - SAVAGE MINING COMPANY
    - Ledgers
      - Pay roll records, 1861-69 (Box 70a, Folder 1178)
      - Pay roll records, 1872-77 (Box 70b, Folder 1179)
      - Pay roll records, 1872-77 (Box 70c, Folder 1180)
      - Pay roll records, 1872-77 (Box 70d, Folder 1181)
      - Pay roll records, 1880-84 (Box 70e, Folder 1182)
        See also: Oversize, Box 89, folder 1442
      - Pay roll records, 1886-87
        See: Oversize, Box 89, folder 1443
      - Pay roll records, 1892-93, n.d.
        See: Oversize, Box 89, folder 1444
    - Daybooks
      - Time book, 1870-73 (Box 70, Folder 1183-1194)
      - Time book, 1873 Jan-Feb
        See: Oversize, Box 89, folder 1445
      - Time books, 1873-1888 (Box 71, Folder 1195)
      - Time books, 1873-1888 (Box 71a, Folder 1196)
      - Time books, 1873-1888 (Box 71b, Folder 1197)
      - Time books, 1873-1888 (Box 71c, Folder 1198)
      - Time Books, 1873-1888 (Box 71d, Folder 1199-1210)
      - Time books, 1888-1889 (Box 72, Folder 1211-1218)
      - Time books, 1889-1892 (Box 73, Folder 1219-1229)
      - Time books, 1892-1898 (Box 74, Folder 1230-1241)
      - Time books, 1898-1901 (Box 75, Folder 1242-1244)
      - Miscellaneous, 1891 Feb 10 (Box 75, Folder 1245)
      - Pay receipts, 1866-1868 (Box 75, Folder 1246-1264)
      - Pay receipts, 1868-1872 (Box 76, Folder 1265-1298)
      - Pay receipts, 1877-1879 (Box 78, Folder 1326-1335)
      - Pay receipts, 1880 (Box 79, Folder 1336-1341)
      - Pay receipts, 1893 (Box 79, Folder 1342)
      - Pay receipts, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1343)
  - SCORPION MINING COMPANY
    - Pay roll record, 1879-1883 (Box 79a, Folder 1344)
    - Pay roll records, drafts, 1880, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1345)
  - WHITE & MURPHY
    - Time book, 1861-1862 (Box 79, Folder 1346)
  - UNIDENTIFIED PAY ROLL RECORDS
    - Pay roll record, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1347)
    - Miscellaneous, 1884 Jun 8 (Box 79, Folder 1348)
- Tax Records, 1865-1903; Series VII
  Series VII, Tax Records, is arranged alphabetically by company name and within each company records are chronologically arranged.
  - EAST SIERRA MINING COMPANY
    - State and county tax statements, 1895-96
      See: Oversize, Box 90, folder 1446
  - HALE & NORCROSS MINING COMPANY
    - State and county tax statements, 1883-85,1887
      See: Oversize, Box 90, folder 1447
  - JUSTICE MINING COMPANY
    - State and county tax statements, 1894-95
      See: Oversize, Box 90, folder 1448
  - SAVAGE MINING COMPANY
    - State and county tax statements, 1866-1903
      See: Oversize, Box 90, folder 1449-51
    - Poll tax records, 1865
      See: Oversize, Box 90, folder 1452
  - SCORPION MINING COMPANY
    - State and county tax statements, 1895-96
      See: Oversize, Box 90, folder 1453
  - SOUTH COMSTOCK MINING COMPANY
    - State and county tax statements, 1894-96
      See: Oversize, Box 90, folder 1454
  - UNIDENTIFIED TAX RECORDS
    - Notes, 1882-83
      See: Oversize, Box 90, folder 1455
- Mining Company Forms, ca.1860-1900; Series VIII; 0.25; (1 box)
  Series VIII, Mining Company Forms, containing blank forms, is arranged parallel to the collection; forms that could be found in a former series are listed under that series title. Forms that are produced by agencies outside the mining companies have been placed at the end of the Series.
  - EXECUTIVE RECORDS (SERIES I)
    - Office of the Fulton Foundry, ca. 187- (Box 80, Folder 1349)
    - Superintendent's Office. Hale & Norcross Silver Mining Company, ca. 188- (Box 80, Folder 1350)
    - Superintendent's Office. Savage Mining Company, ca. 188- (Box 80, Folder 1351)
    - In account with T. H. Ralston, Commission Stock Broker, ca. 187-
      See: Oversize, Box 91, folder 1456
  - OPERATIONS REPORTS (SERIES II)
    - Weekly Report. Hale & Norcross S. M. Co., ca. 188- (Box 80, Folder 1352)
    - Daily Report. Hale & Norcross S. M. Co., n.d. (Box 80, Folder 1353)
    - Savage Silver Mining Company. Daily Record of Operations in Mine. Daily Record of Pumping Operations, ca. 1877 (Box 80, Folder 1354)
    - Daily Report of Men Employed in Savage Mine, ca. 18-- (Box 80, Folder 1355)
    - Weekly Report of Men Employed in Savage Mine, ca. 189- (Box 80, Folder 1356)
    - Received from Savage M. Co. ____ Cars of Ore...to Nevada Mill, ca. 189- (Box 80, Folder 1357)
    - The United Comstock Mining Co. Underground Survey's Daily Report, ca. 192- (Box 80, Folder 1358)
    - Time Card. Supplies Used., n.d. (Box 80, Folder 1359)
  - ORE AND BULLION RECORDS (SERIES III)
    - Superintendent's Office, Gould & Curry Silver Mining Company. [smelting and assaying receipt], ca. 186- (Box 80, Folder 1360)
    - Hale & Norcross Silver Mining Co. Statement of Bullion Produced, ca. 187-
      See: Oversize, Box 91, folder 1457
    - Memorandum of Bullion from Hale & Norcross Mine, Assayed at Hale & Norcross Assay Office, ca. 187-
      See: Oversize, Box 91, folder 1458
    - Savage Assay Office. Ore Assay Report, ca. 188- (Box 80, Folder 1361)
    - For the Sutro Tunnel Co. Statement of Ore Extracted, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 1362)
    - Statement for the Comstock Tunnel Co., ca. 189-
      See: Oversize, Box 91, folder 1459
    - Ore_____Mill,_____1872. [assay report], ca. 1872
      See: Oversize, Box 91, folder 1460
  - FINANCIAL RECORDS (SERIES IV)
    - Bank of California, Virginia City, Nevada, ca. 187-, 190- (Box 80, Folder 1363)
    - Belcher S. M. Co. [receipt], ca. 188- (Box 80, Folder 1364)
    - Best and Belcher Mining Company [receipt], ca. 189- (Box 80, Folder 1365)
    - Brunswick Joint Shaft No. 1, (Savage, Chollar and Potosi Mining Companies), ca. 189- (Box 80, Folder 1366)
    - Chollar Mining Company [receipt], ca. 190- (Box 80, Folder 1367)
    - Gould & Curry Silver Mining Company [receipt], ca. 189- (Box 80, Folder 1368)
    - Savage Mining Company [receipt], ca. 187-, 188- (Box 80, Folder 1369)
    - The United Comstock Mines Co. Local Warehouse Requisition, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 1370)
  - INVENTORY REPORTS (SERIES V)
    - Savage Mining Company. Store House report, ca. 1872
      See: Oversize, Box 94, folder 1474
  - PAY ROLL RECORDS (SERIES VI)
    - Savage Mine. [receipt for pay], ca. 188- (Box 80, Folder 1371)
  - TAX RECORDS (SERIES VII)
    - Original list of the Net Proceeds of the _____ Mine, for quarter ending---, ca. 188- (Box 80, Folder 1372)
    - Statement of Taxable Property within Storey County, Nevada, ca. 188-, 190-
      See: Oversize, Box 91, folder 1461
  - OTHER FORMS
    - Application [for county support], ca. 18-- (Box 80, Folder 1373)
    - Form No. 2. The Western Union Telegraph Company, ca. 188- (Box 80, Folder 1374)
    - Know all men by these presents: [Crocker's blank no. 1643-Proxy], ca. 188- (Box 80, Folder 1375)
    - [Oath of office], n.d. (Box 80, Folder 1376)
    - [U.S. Post Office] Application for Money Order, ca. 189- (Box 80, Folder 1377)
- Tailings, 1871-1942; Series IX; 0.5; (2 boxes)
  Series IX, Tailings, contains material found with the mining records, but not considered corporate records. Miscellaneous company records, however, have been placed at the end of this series. This material is arranged alphabetically.
  - Book catalogs and lists (Box 81, Folder 1378)
  - "The Comstocks Slide Gradually Down the Scale:" newspaper article, [1879] (Box 81, Folder 1379)
  - Democratic Party: Official Proceedings of National Democratic Convention (Chicago: Cambron, Amberg & Co.), 1892 (Box 81, Folder 1380)
  - Democratic Party: Regular Democratic Primary Ticket for delegates to the State [Nevada] Convention to be held May 29, 1892 (Box 81, Folder 1381)
  - [Democratic] political speech, [1888] (Box 81, Folder 1382)
  - Fireman's Fund Insurance Company: financial statement, 1874 Dec 31 (Box 81, Folder 1383)
  - The Forum: advertising flyer, 1892 (Box 81, Folder 1384)
  - Foundries: notice of fee changes at Virginia City, Gold Hill, Silver City, 1871 Dec 1 (Box 81, Folder 1385)
  - Keating family: personal papers, 1888 Jun (Box 81, Folder 1386)
  - Lovelock, Humboldt County: petition by the citizens regarding the postmaster position, n.d. (Box 81, Folder 1387)
  - Mines, Miners and Mining Interests of the United States in 1882: advertising flyer and specimen illustration from book, ca. 1882 (Box 81, Folder 1388)
  - Photograph of eight miners from the Comstock Lode, n.d. (Box Art 1388a)
  - "Preston is Pleased:" newspaper article, May 14 (Box 81, Folder 1389)
  - Recipes, n.d. (Box 81, Folder 1390)
  - Self-instruction in Practical Business Qualifications, by Charles S. McNair (San Francisco: J. Dewing Company), 1890 (Box 81a, Folder 1391)
  - Stock prices: newspaper article, 1889 Aug 10 (Box 81, Folder 1392)
  - Storey County Tax List for 1889. Printed by Wm. Sutherland, Virginia City, Nevada., 1889 Sep 2
    See: Oversize, Box 91, folder 1462
  - Storey County Oaths of Office for Clerk, Inspector, or Judge of election, 1890 Aug (Box 81, Folder 1393)
  - Tannehill family: personal papers, 1925, 1942 (Box 81, Folder 1394)
  - Virginia City Mining School Association (formerly Comstock Extension Class of Nevada State University): minutes, 1900-19 (Box 81b, Folder 1395)
  - Miscellaneous mining records, 1884-87, n.d. (Box 81, Folder 1396)
- Artifacts, Series X; 3.75; (3 boxes)
  Series X, Artifacts, contains objects from the mining offices in Virginia City, Nevada.
  - Canvas bag: "L.F., L.P. & L.W. Extra finish Drop Shot, San Francisco" (Box 81c, Folder 1396a)
  - Canvas bank bag: "The Crocker-Woolworth National Bank of San Francisco" (Box 81c, Folder 1396b)
  - Crucibles, three (Box 81c, Folder 1396c)
  - Desk box, wooden (Box 81c, Folder 1396)
  - Door knocker (Box 81c, Folder 1396e)
  - Hand-held scale in wooden box (Box 81d, Folder 1396)
  - Iron jar (Box 81d, Folder 1396g)
  - Light fixture (Box 81d, Folder 1396h)
  - Mail box (Box 81d, Folder 1396i)
  - Miner's lunch pail (Box 81d, Folder 1396j)
  - Mining lamp (Box 81d, Folder 1396k)
  - Mortar (Box Art 1396l)
  - Pestle (Box Art 1396l2)
  - Silver bar mold (Box 81e, Folder 1396m)
  - Tobacco box: "Union Leader Cut Plug" (Box 81e, Folder 1396n)
  - Surveyor's Vernier Compass, face engraved J. Blattner - St. Louis, Mo., includes both sight vanes and compass cover, undated (Box 81f)
  - Mining lamp (Box 81g)
  - Scale in wooden box, made by Howe, New York, undated (Box 81g)
- Oversize, 10.25; (13 boxes)
  Oversize contains oversize material from Series I-IX, and in a parallel arrangement.
  - EXECUTIVE RECORDS
    - General Records
      - Correspondence, 1879-84 (Box 82, Folder 1397)
      - Agreements, indentures and deeds, 1860-65 (Box 82, Folder 1398)
      - Notes regarding mines and mine claims, 1892, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 1399)
      - Notes regarding city lots, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 1400)
    - Hillside Water Company
      - Maps, notes, and papers regarding water and land claims (Box 82, Folder 1401)
    - Savage Mining Company
      - Insurance policies on superintendent's office and dwelling, 1867-80 (Box 82, Folder 1402)
  - OPERATION RECORDS
    - Chollar-Norcross-Savage Shaft Co.
      - Statement of operations, 1880-84 (Box 83, Folder 1403-07)
      - Statement of operations, 1885-86, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 1408-09)
    - Savage Mining Company
      - Savage Mine
        - Monthly reports of material consumed, 1868-69 (Box 84, Folder 1410)
        - Report of material used in building new hoisting works, 1874-75, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 1411)
  - ORE AND BULLION RECORDS
    - Savage Mining Company
      - Memoranda of Bullion
        - Gould and Curry, 1866-67 (Box 85, Folder 1412-13)
        - Savage, [1868]-70 (Box 85, Folder 1414-16)
      - Assays of Ore per Samples
        - Summaries of wagon and pulp samples, 1868-70 (Box 86, Folder 1417)
        - [Daybook]: car samples, 1892 (Box 86, Folder 1418)
      - Statements for Sutro Tunnel Co., 1890-96 (Box 86, Folder 1419)
      - Ore shipped from mine--bullion rec'd and shipped to San Francisco, 1866 (Box 86, Folder 1420)